# **SEAN JIN**



## **SUMMARY**

Determined Intern working with AI, Machine Learning, and Statistics for the past 2 years. Demonstrated talent and interest in Product Development, Machine Learning, and Statistics in the construction, finance, sports, and video game industry. Skilled in multi-tasking and understanding design and bigger scope of the use cases and user stories.

## **EDUCATION**

Bachelor of Science, Statistics & Machine Learning, Expected in 12/2020 Carnegie Mellon University - Pittsburgh, PA Additional Major in Cognitive Science | GPA: 3.24

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

# Al Integrations & Development Intern, 06/2020 to 08/2020 Cortex-Vertical Inc. - Englewood Cliffs, NJ

Created Azure custom models to tag photos of NBA players as metadata Integrated ffmpeg to divide the video into several jpg images for the model to read for preprocessing

Initiated POC development between Cortex-Vertical Inc and Monster Energy for joint project on integrating Azure into Open Text Media Management Developed several UML Diagrams that showcased development of the project for the next 3 months

# Sports Capstone, 01/2020 to 05/2020 Carnegie Mellon Softball Team - Pittsburgh, PA

Cleaned 1000+ NCAA Division 3 Softball Games of data into an R-shiny app Derived probabilities of bunting and stealing for any state of the game Developed text analysis that analyzes 600,000+ different play-by-play data Created user friendly interface with R-shiny that easily projected the information needed by the coach

10-716 Teacher Assistant, 02/2020 to 05/2020 Machine Learning Department - Pittsburgh, PA

# Machine Learning Research Assistant, 11/2019 to 03/2020 AiPEX Lab - Pittsburgh, PA

Utilized parallel Q-Learning using multiprocessing reduced learning rate by 50% Implemented multi-armed bandit to navigate randomized location of a goal

## Data Science/Full Stack Intern, 06/2019 to 09/2019 CertAlnBuild - Remote

Developed a Web App that displays costs of buildings through Google Maps Utilized Sklearn and SQL Alchemy to create prediction for building costs for data Incorporated HTML, CSS, and bootstrap to create the interface of the MVP Pushed Flask into the website development and login structure of the app

# Teacher Assistant, 06/2016 to 08/2018 M.E.K Review - Palisades Park, NJ

Taught other Teacher Assistants to be efficient, resulted in 30% in workflow Developed habits and improved grading efficiency and accuracy by 20%

#### CONTACT

Phone: 2015801534 Email: seanj@andrew.cmu.edu

https://github.com/seanjincmu/myprojects

https://seandjin.com/

https://www.linkedin.com/in/sean-d-jin/

# **PROJECTS**

# Estimated Taxi Travel Time | Fall 2019

Extracted new features based on Taxi-Zone location within New York City

Utilized Neural Networks to compare it to other algorithms through Sklearn

Reduced RMSE by 99% from simple linear regression to XGBoost in prediction

## Gotta Graph Them All | Fall 2019

Implemented PCA to differentiate types of Pokémon based on base stats using kernlab

Extracted Pokémon base stats to see the distributions between each of Pokémon

Produced graphics that display different attributes of the Pokémon Kaggle using ggplot

## **PVP Platform | Spring 2018**

Created enemies that had different mechanics to be an obstacle for a PvP game

Implemented 4 different classes that have different skills and attributes

Created interface for players to interact with using tkinter **League of Legends eSports: NA Challenger | Fall 2017** 

Utilized Massey and Colley methods to visualize ranking results of all teams

Collected data that portrays kill-death ratio and win-loss ratio by accumulating matches

## **CERTIFICATIONS**

JPMorgan Software Engineering Virtual Experience KPMG Data Analytics Consulting Virtual Internship

# SKILLS

**Python**: Proficient - **R:** Intermdiate - **SQL**: Intermdiate **Java**: Intermediate - **C**: Intermediate - **SML**: Intermediate

## **EXTRA CURRICULARS**

CMU Powerlifting Club: Founder, State Champion Central Church: Discipleship Group Leader Lunar Gala: Model